The Power of the Dog is a drama, western film directed by Jane Campion.
A domineering but charismatic rancher wages a war of intimidation on his brother's
new wife and her teen son, until long-hidden secrets come to light.
Phil Burbank, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Peter Gordon, played by Kodi Smit-McPhee.
Rose Gordon, played by Kirsten Dunst.
George Burbank, played by Jesse Plemons.
Lola, played by Thomasin McKenzie.
Mrs. Lewis, played by Geneviève Lemon.
The Power of the Dog is a 2021 Western psychological drama
film written and directed by Jane Campion.
It is based on Thomas Savage's 1967 novel.
The film stars Benedict Cumberbatch, Kirsten Dunst,
Jesse Plemons, and Kodi Smit-McPhee.
Set in Montana in 1925 and filmed mostly in rural Otago, the film is an international co-production
between New Zealand, Australia, the United Kingdom, the United States, and Canada.
The Power of the Dog premiered at the 78th Venice International Film Festival on 2
September 2021, where Campion won the Silver Lion for Best Direction.
The film had a limited theatrical release in November 2021, and was
released to stream worldwide on Netflix on 1 December 2021.
The Power of the Dog was acclaimed by critics, who praised Campion's direction and
screenplay, and the cinematography, score, and four lead performances.
It was widely regarded as one of the best films of 2021, appearing on many top-ten lists, and received many accolades, including a leading 12 nominations at the 94th Academy
Awards, among them Best Picture, Best Actor for Cumberbatch, Best Supporting Actor for both Plemons and Smit-McPhee, and Best Supporting Actress for Dunst.
Campion won Best Director, making the film the first to win only in that category since The
Graduate (1967); its 11 losses tied the record for most in Oscars history.
It was named one of the best films of 2021 by the American Film Institute, and received seven nominations at the 79th Golden Globe
Awards, winning Best Motion Picture – Drama, Best Supporting Actor – Motion Picture for Smit-McPhee, and Best Director.
It received ten nominations at the 27th Critics' Choice Awards, winning four, including Best Picture, and received
eight nominations at the 75th British Academy Film Awards, winning Best Direction and Best Film.
It has since been cited as among the best films of
the 2020s and of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based
on novel or book, sadism, sexuality, widow.
The tone is emotional and intense.